The Bailey Collection
The Bailey Collection
- Miscellaneous deeds relating to Lancashire, [c 1265]-1859; GB/418/B31/1-B33/200; GB/418/Bailey/13; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance of lands and tenements in Copphull and Worthington, 1405; GB/418/B32/79; GB/418/Bailey/13/82; Chetham's Library
    from John, son of William de Worthyngton, to John, son of Radulph de Standish and Richard, son of Thomas de Worthynton
  - Conveyance from Radulph de Worthington to John de Langley, vicar of Walton of a messuage, 1440; GB/418/B32/80; GB/418/Bailey/13/83; Chetham's Library
    Coppull, Worthington and Turton
    Witnesses: Radulph de Radcliff, William de…, John de Birkened
  - Conveyance of messuages, lands and tenements in Coppull, 4 Jan 1521; GB/418/B32/81; GB/418/Bailey/13/84; Chetham's Library
    from Richard Worthington of Blaynscogh, gent to William Molyneux of Sefton and Edward Molyneux, Rector of Sefton, John ffaryngton of ffaryngton, gent and Henry, son of Henry Banastre
  - Final Concord concerning land in Kuredon (Cuerdon), 1574; GB/418/B32/82; GB/418/Bailey/13/85; Chetham's Library
    Cuerdon, Walton, Dalton, Chorley and Samlesbury
    between Nicholas Blacklagh, gent and Radulphus Critchelawe plaintiff and William Woodcock, gent, deforciant concerning 8 messuages, 2 cottages, 6 gardens, 6 orchards, 100 acres of land, 60 acres of meadow, 100 acres of pasture, 20 acres of wood, 200 acres of furze, 20 acres of moss in Kuredon
  - Recovery of seisin, 11 Aug 1396; GB/418/B32/83; GB/418/Bailey/13/86; Chetham's Library
    by Radulph de Worthinton against Thomas Gerrard, Christopher and Thomas son of Richard de Kirk of Dirnyll - 2 messuages, 30 acres of land, 6 acres of meadow, 6 acres of wood, 6 acres of pasture. Possession to be granted by John Boteler, Sheriff of Leylandshire
  - Royal brief - James, son of Christopher Standish and William Anderton. Recovery by James Molyneux and others against Thomas Standish of the manor of Duxbury and Heapey, 27 Sep 1506; GB/418/B32/84; GB/418/Bailey/13/87; Chetham's Library
  - Receipts from Ranulf de Dacre, Lord of Gyllysland to Petra de Worthington of £10 in part payment of 24 marks, 1364; GB/418/B32/85; GB/418/Bailey/13/88; Chetham's Library
    Eccleston
  - Conveyance from Thomas de Clayton and Richard de Staynolf, chaplains to Edward de Lathom of lands and tenements in Eccleston, 1382; GB/418/B32/86; GB/418/Bailey/13/89; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Geoffrey de Wrightyngton, Richard de Rigby, John, Wen, Roland de Tanlegh, William de Tunlegh
  - Bond in £20 from Richard Wodecok to John Wodecok to observe covenant in a deed, 1413; GB/418/B32/87; GB/418/Bailey/13/90; Chetham's Library
    Farington and Cuerden
  - Acquittance from Richard Boteler, land of Browneswere to Sir John Croft, Lord of Dalton in Kuerdale of 60s in silver for his farm in Frekulton (Freckleton), 1386; GB/418/B32/88; GB/418/Bailey/13/91; Chetham's Library
  - Bond in £20, 1 Aug 1461; GB/418/B32/89; GB/418/Bailey/13/92; Chetham's Library
    from Margaret, wife of Bartholemew de Scharpuls, Joanna wife of William de Longdon, Cecilia wife of Thomas de Scharpuls, Gerald son of Thomas and Cecilia, Giles the brother of Gerlad, Robert Byrley and Agnes the wife of Roland to Seth Wodecoke to abide the award of William Banastre, Sir Geffrey Hesketh and Laurence Anderton
  - Conveyance of land and tenements in Shacurlegh (Shakerley), 1379; GB/418/B32/90; GB/418/Bailey/13/93; Chetham's Library
    from Thomas de Clayton, chaplain and William de Merser, chaplain to Thomas, son of Richard del Bonk, his wife Joanna, and his heirs
    Witnesses: John son of Adam de Clayton, John de ffaryngton Junior, Robert de Pynyngton
  - Conveyance of lands and tenements in Shakerleye (Shakerley in Heapey), 25 Apr 1379; GB/418/B32/91; GB/418/Bailey/13/94; Chetham's Library
    from Richard del Bonk of Whithull and Elena his wife to Thomas Clayton, chaplain and William le Mercer chaplain
    Witnesses: John son of Adam de Clayton, John Pinyngton Junior, William del ffalde Worthynges, Rob. de Pynyngton, John Walle
  - Conveyance from Thomas del Bonk of Hepay to John de Alston, vicar of Leyland and Peter de Wygan, 1399; GB/418/B32/92; GB/418/Bailey/13/95; Chetham's Library
    Heapey, Whithull and Chorley
    Witnesses: Radulphus de Clayton, Richard del Croke, William de Leyland
  - Quitclaim of messuages, lands and tenements in Hepay, Chorlegh and Whithall, 1402; GB/418/B32/93; GB/418/Bailey/13/96; Chetham's Library
    from Thomas del Bonk of Shakerlegh to John de Alston, vicar of Leyland and William le Mercer, chaplain
    Witnesses: Radulphus de Clayton, John de ffarington, Thurston de Anderton, William de Anderton, Richard de Croke
  - Conveyance from Thurstan del Bonke to Edward de Clayton, clerk, William Banastre and Margaret daughter of Robert Hoghton of land at 'Shakerley' in Hepay, 14 Nov 1445; GB/418/B32/94; GB/418/Bailey/13/97; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Adam de Clayton, John de Clayton, James de Anderton
  - Conveyance from Thurstan and Richard Mawdeslaye to Thurston Bank son of Richard Bank and Agnes his wife of a messuage called Shakerley, 13 May 1507; GB/418/B32/95; GB/418/Bailey/13/98; Chetham's Library
    Heapey
  - Conveyance from Thurston, son of Richard Bank to Thurstan and Richard Mawdesley of a messuage called 'Shakerley' in Heapay, 12 May 1507; GB/418/B32/96; GB/418/Bailey/13/99; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Thurston Bank to Evan Haydok of 'Shakerley' in Heapay, 11 Jan 1509; GB/418/B32/97; GB/418/Bailey/13/100; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Thurston Bank to Evan Haydok of land called 'Shakerley' in Heapey, 9 Jan 1509; GB/418/B32/98; GB/418/Bailey/13/101; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Evan Haydok to William Lunt, rector of Brynhill and Robert Swannys senior of Land called Shakerley in Heapey, 9 Aug 1511; GB/418/B32/99; GB/418/Bailey/13/102; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Evan Haydok to William Lunt of land called 'Shakerley' in Heapey, 29 Aug 1511; GB/418/B32/100; GB/418/Bailey/13/103; Chetham's Library
  - Quitclaim from Thurston son of Richard Bank to Vano Haydok of a messuage called 'Shacurley' and lands called 'Mawdisley', and 'Blachehohe' in Heapey and Chorley, 20 Apr 1523; GB/418/B32/101; GB/418/Bailey/13/104; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Giles Haydok to Van Haydok of land called 'Shakerley' in Heapey, 8 Jun 1567; GB/418/B32/102; GB/418/Bailey/13/105; Chetham's Library
  - Copy conveyance from Giles Haydok to Van Haydok of land called 'Shakerley' in Heapey, (8 Jun 1567); GB/418/B32/103; GB/418/Bailey/13/106; Chetham's Library
  - Authorization from Giles, younger son of Symon Haydock, to his younger brother Thomas to receive a deed of entail made by Van Haydok, eldest brother of Giles of Shakerley in Heapey, 20 Jun 1567; GB/418/B32/104; GB/418/Bailey/13/107; Chetham's Library
  - Family settlement from William Lunt, rector of Brynhill and Robert Swannyse, gent to Evan Haydock of messuage and tenement called 'Shakerley' (in Heapey), 1 Sep 1511; GB/418/B32/105; GB/418/Bailey/13/108; Chetham's Library
    Remainder to Evan's wife Joan for life
  - Conveyance from Vane, eldest son of Simon Haydocke of Burnley, gent to Giles brother of Vane and younger son of Simon of land and tenements in Heapey, 20 Jun 1567; GB/418/B32/106; GB/418/Bailey/13/109; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Vane Haydok to Giles Haydok of Shakerley in Heapey, 20 Jun 1567; GB/418/B32/107; GB/418/Bailey/13/110; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Richard, son of Ade del Strete to his brother John of land received from Hugh Gogard (in Heath Charnock), nd [c 1275]; GB/418/B32/108; GB/418/Bailey/13/111; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from William Standley, Lord Mounteagle to Thomas Walmesley and Robert Charnock of lands, tenements and manor of Heath Charnock, 12 Jan 1575; GB/418/B32/109; GB/418/Bailey/13/112; Chetham's Library
  - Final concord from Roger Brodhunt and James Brucke to Richard Docksie and Margaret his wife of land, a cottage, a barn, and woodland in Heaton for 60 marks, 1603; GB/418/B32/110; GB/418/Bailey/13/113; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from John son of Algey Gogar to Ad de Strata Anabyl his wife and their daughter Agnes of land in Hedenewanysbothestud in Helay, nd [c 1270]; GB/418/B32/111; GB/418/Bailey/13/114; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Adam de Dokesbury, Henry his son, Hugh Gogar, Robert his son, Benedict the clerk, Robert le Perfiunt, William son of Thomas
  - Bond in £100 from Hugh Whitle of Horwich to Henry, son and heir of Radulph Marsden of Hoillesden in Over Darwen, 11 Mar 1624; GB/418/B32/112; GB/418/Bailey/13/115; Chetham's Library
  - Authorisation from James Yate of the Hunter Holme in the Forest of Pendle, 18 Apr 1632; GB/418/B32/113; GB/418/Bailey/13/116; Chetham's Library
    Ightenhill and Pendle Forest
    to Edward Robinson of the Old Laund, Nicholas Bancroft of Habergham, Anne Underhill, Nicholas Townley Esq of Royle and Isabel his wife
  - Final Concord concerning land in Skelmergh cum Patten in Kirkby Kendall, 1702; GB/418/B32/114; GB/418/Bailey/13/117; Chetham's Library
    from John Brathwaite, Humfrey plaintiffs, Hutchinson, Frances his wife and Dorothy Brathwaite to William Jordanson deforciant
  - Conveyance from William de Livesey to John Del Kirke, Rector of Barnhull of lands and tenements in Levesay and Walton le Dale, 6 Mar 1452; GB/418/B32/115; GB/418/Bailey/13/118; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Richard Hoghton, Henry Langton, John Banastre of Walton, William Banastre of Walton, Geoffrey de Levesay
  - Conveyance from John del Kyrke, Rector of Burnhull to William de Levesay of messuages, lands and tenements in Levesay (Livesey) and Walton le Dale, 15 Nov 1456; GB/418/B32/116; GB/418/Bailey/13/119; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from William Levesay to Katerine his wife of annual rent of 35s for life from a messuage in Livesay and Walton (le Dale), 8 Nov 1456; GB/418/B32/117; GB/418/Bailey/13/120; Chetham's Library
  - Marriage settlement between William Levesay and Seth Woodecok William, son and heir apparent of Seth to mary Alison, daughter of William, nd [?15th century]; GB/418/B32/118; GB/418/Bailey/13/121; Chetham's Library
    Livesey and Walton le Dale
  - Conveyance from Henry Ploket to Warine, son of William de la Broc of lands in Langton (Longton, near Preston), nd [c 1300]; GB/418/B32/119; GB/418/Bailey/13/122; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Nicholas de Botiler, Henry de Bekanishoue, Thomas Starki, William de Hole, Warin de Holwike, Adam de Buri
  - Indented bond for payment of £8 13s 4d made between Robert de Chorleton and Roger his brother and Ranulf de Hyde and John de Hulme, 14 Feb 1369; GB/418/B33/120; GB/418/Bailey/13/123; Chetham's Library
    Manchester
  - Bond in £43 6s 8d from Thomas de Worthyngton, 7 Dec 1370; GB/418/B33/121; GB/418/Bailey/13/124; Chetham's Library
    Nicholas de Worthyngton his brother, William de Bradeshagh of Hawgh, Robert de Chernok, Hugh de Worthyngton and Thomas his brother to John de Wyke of Scredyngton and Thurston Holland
  - Conveyance from Edward Hilton to Elizabeth his wife of annual rent of 6s 8d for a tenement, 2 Aug 1549; GB/418/B33/122; GB/418/Bailey/13/125; Chetham's Library
    giving one penny to her for seisin of the house he lives in
  - Summary of the case against Mr. Richard Murray, Warden of Manchester Collegiate Church, placed before the King's Commissioners, 4 Jun 1635; GB/418/B33/123; GB/418/Bailey/13/126; Chetham's Library
    This document is of particular interest since it corroborates and complements the accounts of Murray's misdeeds given by Raines in The Rector of Manchester, Part II, Chetham Society, New Series Vol 6 pp 112-122.
  - Conveyance from Alice, formerly wife of Richard de Pilkyngton to Henry de Pylkynton of land in Great Lever (Manchester), 1368; GB/418/B33/124; GB/418/Bailey/13/127; Chetham's Library
  - Quitclaim from Alice, daughter of Alan de Maudeslegh (Mawdsley) to Master Radulph de Tunstall of 3 acres of land and waste, 1329; GB/418/B33/125; GB/418/Bailey/13/128; Chetham's Library
  - Quitclaim from Thomas son of Roger de Tunstall to William Sparowe of Mawdesley of land and tenements in Mawdesley, 1360; GB/418/B33/126; GB/418/Bailey/13/129; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Robert de Chalirton, Roger de Clifton, William de Hevour, Thomas de fford, John de Walker of Croston
  - Conveyance from Thomas fflemyng to William Sparowe of Maudeslegh and Emme his wife of messuages and tenements in Croston, 1370; GB/418/B33/127; GB/418/Bailey/13/130; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Thomas Banastre del Bonk, William Banastre de Brotherton, Richard de Rigby, John de Heskyn, Adam de Maudeslegh
  - Conveyance from John Kirke, parson of Birnkhill and Thurston Shoroke, Vicar of Leyland to Joan, wife of Thomas Maudesley of land in Maudesley and Wrightington, 1477; GB/418/B33/128; GB/418/Bailey/13/131; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Henry Banastre sen., Christopher Standishe, William Chorley
  - Quitclaim from Robert, son of Roger de Stiholme to John Wodcoke of 3 acres of land in Meller (Mellor, Lancs), 24 Jul 1429; GB/418/B33/129; GB/418/Bailey/13/132; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: John de Levesay, John Banastre of Lostok, John Banastre of Walton
  - Conveyance of land at Melling in Sefton from Robert de Molyneux to Amaricia daughter of Richard de Lond, nd [c 1265]; GB/418/B33/130; GB/418/Bailey/13/133; Chetham's Library
    Remainder to her sister Haurisia
    Witnesses: Robert de Burun, William de Antre, William de Manwell, Thomas de Thorp
  - Quitclaim from Richard, son of Adam son of Hugh de Melling, to Hugh, son of William del Lond of land between Wadakerbroc and the land of Henry le Taylour jun, 1330; GB/418/B33/131; GB/418/Bailey/13/134; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Robert de Nevill, William de Molyneux of Sefton, William Gerard, Henry de Achton, Robert de Buthull
  - Lease from William Boroo of Moche Ecclestone gent to Robert Whytside of Carleton of land, messuages and tenements formerly belonging to Cockersand Monastery, Oct 1562; GB/418/B33/132; GB/418/Bailey/13/135; Chetham's Library
    Terms: £10 31 years
  - Quitclaim from Symon Bryan, chaplain and Gilbert Tayllor of Evesham to John Noteshagh of Hogwyk of land at Penwortham, 1389; GB/418/B33/133; GB/418/Bailey/13/136; Chetham's Library
  - Agreement concerning a deed dated 8 Hen IV, 1413; GB/418/B33/134; GB/418/Bailey/13/137; Chetham's Library
    between (1) Radulph and Johanna de Bolton, John and Katherine Wirden, Robert de Agthton of Agthton and Cecilia his wife, Richard de Rodworth and Alicia his wife
    (2) Richard de Hoghton, William de ffarynton, Richard de Worthinton Sen., Henry de Hoghwyk, Richard Roger de Wirden, John del Croke, arbitrators
    Penwortham, Fishwick, Rybalton, Brockholes, Preston
  - Attornment to give seisin of land and tenements in Preston to Henry de Worthington, 12 Feb 1450; GB/418/B33/135; GB/418/Bailey/13/138; Chetham's Library
    from John Kirke, parson of Burnhall, John Birom, Henry Birkheved and Edward Worthington to Richard Lawde
  - Bond in 20 marks from William de Walton of Preston, spicer to Thomas de Lynesay of Walton de Dale to fulfil award of land in Preston, 1 Sep 1457; GB/418/B33/136; GB/418/Bailey/13/139; Chetham's Library
    to Lawrence of Aynesworth, William Banaster and Thomas of Corwen
  - Conveyance from Sir Piers Legh to Richard Fairhurst of Pemberton of all lands and tenements in Pemberton and Sheryngton, 1 Apr 1474; GB/418/B33/137; GB/418/Bailey/13/140; Chetham's Library
    Pemberton and Sherington
    Rent - 7 marks
  - Conveyance from Thomas Langton of Walton le Dale to his servant John Woodcocke and Edward his son of an annual rent of 48s 4d out of messuages in Preston, 28 Feb 1569; GB/418/B33/138; GB/418/Bailey/13/141; Chetham's Library
    Preston, Kuerdon and Walton
  - Acknowledgement by Symon Haydok of Burnley before Edward French gent Mayor of Preston and Evan Wall, clerk, 9 Aug 1664; GB/418/B33/139; GB/418/Bailey/13/142; Chetham's Library
    that in 1654 he owed £1188 12s to Robert Towneley of Clifton, gent
  - Lease from Thomas Bocher and Ames his wife, daughter and heir of George Sandsforth to William Bamber of Little Carlton of Carr or Clsoe, 10 Dec 1553; GB/418/B33/140; GB/418/Bailey/13/143; Chetham's Library
    Pulton
    Terms - £6 36 years
  - Deed written in Anglo-Norman French, 2 Feb 1371; GB/418/B33/141; GB/418/Bailey/13/144; Chetham's Library
    naming Gilbert de Standisch, parson of Standish, Thomas de Worthyngton, Robert de Ayscheton, Nicholas de Worthyngton, Osmund de Prestecote, William son of Hugh de Worthyngton, Clemence daughter of Henry of Standisch
  - Bond in £30 from Ralph Standisshe of Standish, gent, to Henry Marsh of Tockholes to observe covenants concerning land at Tockholes, 1 Jun 1584; GB/418/B33/142; GB/418/Bailey/13/145; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: William Chorley, Jr, John Greve, clerk, Robert Heald and John, son of Roger Gelibrand
  - Conveyance from John de Eltonheved and Thomas de Worthinton to Nicholas de Worthinton of lands and tenements at Turton, 1377; GB/418/B33/143; GB/418/Bailey/13/146; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Nicholas de Worthynton, Robert del Lowe and Richard Geringon to Thomas de Worthington of land and tenements in Turton, 1385; GB/418/B33/144; GB/418/Bailey/13/147; Chetham's Library
    Turton, Bolton
  - Conveyance from John del Kirke, parson of Burnhall to John Birom, Henry Birkheved and Edward Worthington of messuages, lands and tenements in Turton, 12 Feb 1450; GB/418/B33/145; GB/418/Bailey/13/148; Chetham's Library
  - Counterpart conveyance from Henry de Worthington of messuages, lands and tenements in Turton, 12 Feb 1450; GB/418/B33/146; GB/418/Bailey/13/149; Chetham's Library
    to John del Kirke, parson of Burnhull, John Biron, Henry Birkheved and Edward Worthington
  - Conveyance from Warin de Walton to John Herdhumptes of land in Ulnes Walton, nd [c 1284]; GB/418/B33/147; GB/418/Bailey/13/150; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Thomas Banastre, William Bussitt and others
  - Copy of Wakefield Court Roll, 29 Jan 1591; GB/418/B33/148; GB/418/Bailey/13/151; Chetham's Library
    Ulverthorpe and Burnley
    Refers to Edmund Towneley, Laurence Habergham, Thomas Whittacre, John Wodroffe, Richard son of John Townley, Symon Haddock, John Townley, John Parker, William Barcrofte, John Halstede, Richard Shawe
  - Dispute over the ownership of Urmston Manor, (10 February 1292); GB/418/B33/149; GB/418/Bailey/13/152; Chetham's Library
    Original ms transcription and incomplete translation
  - Conveyance from Robert Banastr, Lord of Walton to Alan Plumber of Walton of land in Walton, nd [13th century]; GB/418/B33/150; GB/418/Bailey/13/153; Chetham's Library
    Walton le Dale
    Witnesses: Richard de Bradesch, Alexander de Kuerdale, Henry, son of Richard Banastre, Geoffrey Banastre, clerk
  - Conveyance from Robert Banastre of Walton to Robert de Baldse of land in Walton le Dale, nd [c 1270]; GB/418/B33/151; GB/418/Bailey/13/154; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: John Devias, Alex. de Kniverdal, Henry Banastre, Geoffrey Banastre, Henry his brother, Richard de Thorp, Gilbert de Foresta, John de Baldse, Henry son of Ralph, Thomas de Bradelee, Henry Balse
  - Quitclaim from Gilbert son of Adam Wachet de Walton to Robert son of Geoffrey Banastre of land in Walton (le Dale), nd [c1290]; GB/418/B33/152; GB/418/Bailey/13/155; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Mathew de Haydock, Alex de Kynesdale, Geoffrey his son, Henry de Blakeburne, Henry Banastre, Richard his son, Richard de Thorp
  - Conveyance from John de Harewode to William son of John de Warin of tenements and 3 acres lying between land of Robert de Fysshewyk and Robert son of Gilber (in Walton le Dale), 1326; GB/418/B33/153; GB/418/Bailey/13/156; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Henry de Blakburn, senior, Henry de Banastre de Walton, John son of Henry de Blackburn, John son of Geoffrey de Walton, Alexander de Longeleghe, Richard the Smith.
  - Conveyance from Robert son of Geoffrey Banastre de Walton to Henry de Lostok and his son Robert of half Banastre's land in Walton (le Dale) and half the land in the gift of Agnes de Bradelegh, 1327; GB/418/B33/154; GB/418/Bailey/13/157; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Henry de Blakeburn, Henry Banastr, John de Walton, James de Lostok, Adam de Balsagh
  - Conveyance from Robert son of Geoffrey to Adam son of Roger de Lynesay, his wife Margery and heirs of land in Walton-in-le-Dale, 1332; GB/418/B33/155; GB/418/Bailey/13/158; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Henry de Blakeburn, John de Blakeburn, John de Walton, Adam de Balshagh, Alexander de Longelegh, John de Bradley, Adam de Harwode
  - Conveyance from John, son of Robert de Balshagh to William, son of Richard de Belyngton, Marjorie and their heirs of 6 acres of land, 1334; GB/418/B33/156; GB/418/Bailey/13/159; Chetham's Library
    Remainder to Henry, son of Henry de Kerdon, Robert de Balshagh, Robert son of Robert the carpenter of Walton
    Witnesses: Henry Banastre, William Banastre, John de Walton, Alex. de Longley
  - Conveyance from Richard Smith of Blyngton in Walton to William, son of John son of Warin de Walton of 1½ acres in Walton (le Dale), 1349; GB/418/B33/157; GB/418/Bailey/13/160; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: Adam de Blakeburne, John de Walton, Henry Banastre, Alexander de Tonge, James de Lostok, Henry de Blakeburne, Adam de Harwode, Adam the Clerk
  - Conveyance from Richard son of Robert de Fysshewyk de Walton to Henry Waryng of Walton of messuages, lands and tenements in Walton-in-le-Dale, 1354; GB/418/B33/158; GB/418/Bailey/13/161; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: John de Banastre, John de Longeleigh, Hugh de Haydok and others
  - Grant in fee from Robert de Lostok, parson of Wigan to Richard Banastre, chaplain of messuages, lands and tenements in Walton (le Dale), 1 Dec 1360; GB/418/B33/159; GB/418/Bailey/13/162; Chetham's Library
  - Attornment from Robert de Lostok, parson of Wigan to Richard de Hansagh to give seisin to Richard Banastre of lands and tenements in Walton (le Dale), 1361; GB/418/B33/160; GB/418/Bailey/13/163; Chetham's Library
  - Attornmentto give seisin to John, son of William de Walton of lands and tenements in Walton (le Dale), 1363; GB/418/B33/161; GB/418/Bailey/13/164; Chetham's Library
    from Robert de Lostocke, rector of Hollingbourne to Richard de Hanschawe
  - Conveyance from Richard Banastre, chaplain to John son of William de Walton of messuage and eight acres in Walton (le Dale), 1363; GB/418/B33/162; GB/418/Bailey/13/165; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from William Careles to Thomas de Worthinton and John de Eltonhed of land and tenements in Walton, Leyes and Turton, 1366; GB/418/B33/163; GB/418/Bailey/13/166; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: John de Worthinton, Hugh de Wrythinton, Henry de Bourgh, Elia de Entwysel
  - Quitclaim from Thomas de Clayton, Chaplain to William son of Richard Wodecok of land in Waltin-in-le-Dale, 1383; GB/418/B33/164; GB/418/Bailey/13/167; Chetham's Library
  - Quitclaim from John son of William de Walton to Robert de Lyneslay of messuages and eight acres in Nethernes, 1407; GB/418/B33/165; GB/418/Bailey/13/168; Chetham's Library
  - Conveyance from Richard de Haydok to John son of Henry Banastre of Walton of messuages, lands and tenements, 1417; GB/418/B33/166; GB/418/Bailey/13/169; Chetham's Library
    4s rent for 6 years
    Witnesses: Edmund de Longeley, William le fletcher of Cholley
  - Conveyance from John de Walton to Thomas de Levesay of land called Wattonesfield in Walton, 1435; GB/418/B33/167; GB/418/Bailey/13/170; Chetham's Library
    Witnesses: William Banastre de Lostok, William de Levesay, John Coke, the clerk
  - Attornment from Richard Nelson to John Banastre to give seisin to William de Levesay of land and tenements in Walton (le Dale), 19 Apr 1435; GB/418/B33/168; GB/418/Bailey/13/171; Chetham's Library